When the streets have gone to Hell, have faith in the devil.
Daredevil is a fantasy, action film directed by Mark Steven Johnson.
A man blinded in a childhood accident fights crime using
his superhumanly-elevated remaining senses.
Matt Murdock / Daredevil, played by Ben Affleck.
Elektra Natchios, played by Jennifer Garner.
Bullseye, played by Colin Farrell.
Wilson Fisk / The Kingpin, played by Michael Clarke Duncan.
Franklin "Foggy" Nelson, played by Jon Favreau.
Young Matt, played by Scott Terra.
Daredevil is a 2003 American superhero film written and directed by Mark Steven Johnson, based on
the Marvel Comics character
of the same name created by Stan Lee and Bill Everett.
The film stars Ben Affleck as Matt Murdock, a blind lawyer who fights for justice in the
courtroom and on the streets of New York as the masked vigilante Daredevil.
Jennifer Garner, Michael Clarke Duncan, Colin Farrell, Joe Pantoliano, Jon
Favreau, and David Keith also star in supporting roles.
The film began development in 1997 at 20th Century Fox and in 1999 transferred to Columbia
Pictures, before New Regency acquired the rights to the character in 2000.
Johnson shot the film primarily in Downtown Los Angeles despite the
Hell's Kitchen, Manhattan setting of the film and comics.
Rhythm and Hues Studios were hired to handle the film's CGI.
Graeme Revell composed the score, which was released on cassette and CD in March 2003, whereas the
various artists' soundtrack album, Daredevil: The Album, was released in February.
Daredevil was released in the United States on
February 14, 2003, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews from critics.
It became the second-biggest February release to that time and went on to a worldwide total gross of
$179.2 million against a production budget of $78 million, becoming a box-office success.
In 2004, an R-rated director's cut of Daredevil was released, reincorporating approximately 30
minutes of the film, and reviews were more positive than for the theatrical version.
A spin-off film, Elektra, with Garner reprising her role as Elektra
Natchios, was released in 2005 to critical and commercial failure.
The rights to the character eventually reverted to Marvel, who rebooted him in the Marvel Cinematic Universe
(MCU) with Charlie Cox in the role, starting with the Netflix self-titled television series.
Garner reprised her role as Elektra in the 2024 film Deadpool & Wolverine.
The film explores themes of blindness and impaired vision,
narration, superhero, based on comic, daredevil.
The tone is intense.